It balanced Binary Tree, also referred to as a high balance binary tree, is defined as a binary tree
in which the height of the left and right up tree of any node differed by not more than one.
Following are the conditions for the height balance binary tree difference between the left and right.
Sub three for any node is not more than one.
This left sub tree is balanced and writes up.
Tree is balanced.
Consider this tree.
F equal to two one.
The F equal to zero difference equal to zero difference is equal to zero four zero and the fifth node
is zero.
So this is a balanced binary tree because if we consider this left and right, this is the left sub
tree.
And that it's arbitrary and we draw a line that it is this that mirrors this is that is right to sub
three and the left sub three.
If we make the difference between these levels that it's sub three and the left sub three, we will
consider it the difference, not more than one.
So either one or zero other than this would be not a balanced binary.
Three.
Consider this binary tree.
If we consider this a level to the right, this is the right sub tree.
And this is the left sub tree.
If we see that difference between them, we have a one level and the second level.
So we have this one and two levels do level difference between the left sub tree and the right set tree.
So the f is the height of the left, the child minus the height of the right child as an absolute value
or modulus.
OK.
It's very simple to detect that it is a balanced three or not.
Just look at the left and the right secretary.
If there is, the difference between the levels is more than one.
Then it will not be a balanced binary tree.
Let's consider a balanced binary tree implementation and see.
We create the note that it is the basic structure of the tree.
And as I told you in the tree section, in the tree lessons when you see a tree, then the node would
contain one reference to the left and one reference to the right.
And the data are contained into like you can make it ends and car or any type of object.
But the data?
And the left pointer and right pointer, then we create a new node method, this new node method that
initialized the node like a constructor for this.
You can make this method or you can make a constructor for their node creation.
OK.
It's very simple.
We initialize the left and the right to null and put the item data equal to the best meter.
I'd check for the height balance.
We create a new method called check height.
Balance took into parameter the root and the height start by the if the left or enclosing the left side
to zero and rotate equal to zero.
We start if root equal equal to null, then the height equal to zero and then return one.
Otherwise, l equal to check a height balance.
This is the left.
We are checking the balance left and the balance to the right.
We are checking the height of the right.
OK.
And with f height left minus right left height minus ride height greater than two.
Or hide right line is left either you can make like consider for the left, like it's equal to five
and the right is equal to three.
Then it is equal greater than or equal to to send it.
There's not a balanced three or the right.
This is the right.
Minus left is if life is greater than life here.
If left is greater than right.
So if we have a three to the left and one to the right, then we don't have a balanced binary.
Returns zero.
OK.
Otherwise, it will return a Boolean expression.
Between Al and so Al and and ah, this is a Boolean expression al either one and are equal to zero or
one.
So this will make a Boolean expression and return a result for this summation.
If we need to test our code, we create a new store in the main new node root left.
Create the No.
Route one left is equal to two exactly like this picture.
Three is the right left.
Left is a four and left is five.
Now I want from you to write this code in your C compiler and lets it check if that it is a balanced
three or not.
I am waiting your.
Answers in the comments below.
And I am waiting your suggestions, your support, your questions or just you may save for us.
Thanks, intercom.
So I am.
I love I love reading your comments.
I love you sharing your comments.
OK, so I'm writing your thoughts.
I'm waiting for answers and I'm waiting for you.
Thank.